Guide to the China Records Project Miscellaneous Personal Papers Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Papers of Individuals: N - Z, Series III
  - Sheets, Margaret
    - Subject and Collected Items: Three-Self Church Statement (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Subject and Collected Items: Committee on China Policy, Apr 1953 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Subject and Collected Items: Church in China Reports, Jul 1987 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Subject and Collected Items: Newsletters Hankow and Anking (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Subject and Collected Items: History of Central China Teacher's College (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Subject and Collected Items: Newspaper Clippings re. China (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Subject and Collected Items: Magazine Articles re. China (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Subject and Collected Items: Chart, China Culture, Map (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Subject and Collected Items: Biographical info. - others (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Subject and Collected Items: Misc. Articles re. Asia, etc. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Subject and Collected Items: Book - Fifty Famous Chinese Tales (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Chinese Language Materials: A Commentary on the Four Books (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Chinese Language Materials: A collection of poems from 18 schools (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Chinese Language Materials: Hymns of universal praise (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Chinese Language Materials: Junior Readers (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Chinese Language Materials: Primers - secular (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Chinese Language Materials: Faith and work Magazines (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Chinese Language Materials: Lang. exercise book (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Chinese Language Materials: Communist Publications (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Chinese Language Materials: Booklets re. Christianity (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Chinese Language Materials: Ten lessons on the Apostle's Creed (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Chinese Language Materials: Wuhang Christian Students Summer Conference, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Chinese Language Materials: Reading Primers (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Chinese Language Materials: An introduction of the new language - Romanized Chinese (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Chinese Language Materials: Selected songs from Peking Opera - Taking Tiger Mountain by Strategy (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Chinese Language Materials: New Testament (Box 12a)
    - Chinese Language Materials: Hymnal, Prayer Book, Memorabilia (Box 12a)
    - Photograph (Box 12a)
  - Shepherd, Clara Sargent and George W.
    Biog. info: Clara Sargent went to China in 1919 as the first female doctor to serve in the field of public health. She worked with the National Council on Health Education and served on the faculty of the Women's College of Physical Education in Shanghai, which later became a department of Ginling College in Nanking. She promoted public health campaigns in China and helped in writing health textbooks for Chinese government schools. In 1921, she married the Rev. Dr. George Shepherd, and served as a physician and public health director under the ABCFM in Shaowu and Foochow in Fukien. She and Rev. Shepherd were evacuated from China shortly before Pearl Harbor.
    - Bound ms.: "Yours in the Bonds of Love" by Clara Sargent and George W. Shepherd (Box 316, Folder 1)
    - Booklet of press clippings and correspondence relating to Dr. Clara Sargent Shepherd., 1908, 1918, 1927, 1934-1938 (Box 316, Folder 2)
    - Bound ms.: "The Sacred Trust of Civilization" by George W. Shepherd (Box 316, Folder 3)
    - Presentation copy of Sian: A Coup D'Etat signed by Mayling Soong Chiang, given to American Board Library by George W. Shepherd, 1937 (Box 316, Folder 4)
  - Sheretz, Dwight Lamar and Margarita Park
    Biog. info: MEFB Soochow (1918-1950)
    - Biographical sketch: "Lamar and Rita Sheretz" written by their daughter, Margarita Sheretz Messersmith, 1973 (Box 188, Folder 8)
  - Shields, Randolph T. (M.D.)
    Biog. info: PS Soochow (1905-1950), Nanking
    - Typescript writings and speeches by RTS re. medical missions in China, 1909-1954 (Box 236, Folder 8)
    - Books: medical textbooks (Box 319, Folder 1)
    - Books: Medical textbooks (Box 320, Folder 1)
  - Shrader, Elizabeth T.*
    Biog. info: ABCFM Foochow (1936-1942) (Mrs. Ralph R.?)
    - Writings by ETS: Typescript ms.: "Baby and a Bamboo Chair", "Canopy of Heaven", "Students-1929" (Box 188, Folder 9-11)
    - Writings by ETS: Articles: "The White Pagoda" from Christian Science Monitor, "The Chinese Renaissance and the Christian Missionary from American Review, May-June 1925, "As Others See Us" from the Pen Woman, oct 1969, "Hope Can Warm a Man" from Light and Life Evangel, Dec 1970, SS lesson re. China by ETS and Ralph Shrader from the Pilgrim Highroad, Aug 1940 (Box 188, Folder 12-14)
    - Typescript writings: misc. (Box 188, Folder 15)
    - Collected material: Issue of the China Forthnightly (Dec 1940), list of Nanking Language School class of 1920, photograph (Soochow?) (Box 188, Folder 16)
    - Three scrolls (Box OV4)
  - Sibley, Horace and Gertrude Haugh
    Biog. info: YMCA Nebraska (1890) CIM Shae-ki-tien, Honan (1891) Lao-ho-kow, Hupeh (1892-1898, 1902) Ku Cheng (1903-1911)
    - Mimeographed memoir: "All the days of Our Life", 1945 (Box 188, Folder 17)
  - Silsby, John Alfred*
    Biog. info: PN South Gate, Shanghai (Lowrie Institute) (1887-1928)
    - Handwritten letters to Father, mother from JAS, 1887 (Box 188, Folder 18)
    - Handwritten letter to JAS from Alexander M. Hudnut, Society of Earnest Works for China, 1890 (Box 188, Folder 19)
    - Letter to His Excellency He-kwen from JAS, to Helen and Robert Silsby from JAS, 1890s?, 1926 (Box 188, Folder 20)
    - Diaries: fragments (1887-1890), pocket-size diary for 1892; Photographs: missionaries and Bible woman (1890s, 1931) (Box 188, Folder 21-22)
  - Simester, Edith (Roeder)
    Biog info: Edith Simester Roeder (1902-1991) was born in Foochow, China where her parents were missionaries. Following her education in the U.S. she taught at the Anglo-Chinese College, a Methodist institution in Fukien from ca. 1930 to 1946. Unable to return to China, she taught at Scarritt College, served in in Brazil for three years, and then was in charge of an Adult Literacy Program in South Korea until 1960. She married Paul Roeder in 1961.
    - Letters to family, incl. reports of war years, Anglo-Chinese College operations in refugee status, 1938 Oct - 1945 Jan (Box 356, Folder 1-2)
    - Letters from others, incl. Lacy, Lin, Ling, 1948 Dec - 1950 Jul (Box 356, Folder 3)
    - Circular letters of Edith Simester, 1930-1956 (Box 356, Folder 4)
    - Writings: "Learning Chinese"; "Home to Foochow"; "Return to Foochow"; "Security - Physical or Spiritual", 1930-ca. 1938 (Box 356, Folder 5)
    - Writings: "My Account of the Japanese Invasion of Foochow", 1938 Oct (Box 356, Folder 6)
    - Writings: "Life With a Refugee School"; "Remaining in Yankow", 1938-1943 (Box 356, Folder 7)
    - "My Trip West to India"; "Airlift", 1943-1944 (Box 356, Folder 8)
    - Other writings of Edith Simester, n.d. (Box 356, Folder 9)
    - Writings of Walter N. Lacy and Eunice Smith Bishop (Box 356, Folder 10)
    - Biographical information, n.d. (Box 356, Folder 11)
    - "China Revisited" - memoir compilation of documents and pictures, 1980 (Box 356, Folder 12)
    - Printed articles, photos, 1937, 1958 (Box 356, Folder 13)
    - Audio cassette tapes of ESR China talks and memorial (5 tapes) (Box 356, Folder 14)
  - Simester, Winifred
    - Photographs re. Foochow, Kuliang, E.Asia Litt. Conf. Japan, etc., 1897, 1903 (Box 188, Folder 26)
  - Simkin, Margaret Simkin, Robert
    Biog. info: AFBM West China Union University Chengtu, Szechwan
    - Printed book of letters: "Letters from Szechwan 1923-1944" by Margaret T. Simkin, 1978 (Box 262, Folder 4)
  - Simpson, Willard J.
    Biog. info: MEFB Peking, Changli, Hopei Peitaiho, Hopeh (L.1928-L.1940)
    - Pamphlet.: "Our Work and Our Play" by Alice and Willard Simpson Changli, China (Box 188, Folder 23)
  - Sites, Evelyn (Mrs. C.M. Lacey)
    Biog. info: WFMS Foochow, Kutien (1896-1941)
    - Writings incl. "The Rose of Sharon--an autobiographical reflection", and 4 other pieces (Box 188, Folder 24)
    - Corres. containing comments re. "The Rose of Sharon" and others., 1971, n.d. (Box 188, Folder 25)
  - Slater, Philip and Phyllis
    Biog. info: BMS Shanghai
    - 11 page account by Rev. J.E. Shoemaker of 40 years' work in Ningpo given at a meeting of missionaries 1934 Oct 2; 2 letters from the Slaters; photographs; letters from Chinese convert., 1934-1938, 1949, 1973-1978 (Box 192, Folder 1)
  - Smith, B. Ward and Trissa Darnall
    Biog. info: YMCA Peking, Kaifeng, Chungking, Tsingtao, Shanghai (1918-1940)
    - Articles in Eng. from Ch. newspapers, mostly on financial topics, 1947, 1948 (Box 192, Folder 2-18)
    - Articles in Eng. from Ch. newspapers, mostly on financial topics, 1946-1948 (Box 193, Folder 1-18)
    - Articles in Eng. from Ch. newspapers (Box 194, Folder 1-5)
  - Smith, Elleroy; Smith, Maybelle (Mrs. Elleroy)*
    Biog. info: PN Ningpo (1916-1950)
    - Correspondence, 1931, 1932 (Box 195, Folder 1)
    - Typescript writings of MCS: "A Brief History of the Missionary Work in the Ningpo Field, 1894-1936", Notes from record books of Ningpo Missionary Association, 1860-1891, 1934, 1936 (Box 195, Folder 2-3)
    - Published articles by MCS: "Christian Beginnings in Ningpo" (from The Chinese Recorder 1937 Nov) (Box 195, Folder 4)
    - Collected material: "A Talk on Forty Years of Missionary Work in the Ningpo - Yu Yao Field" by J.E. Shoemaker, 1934 (Box 195, Folder 5)
    - Diaries of MSC: Five-year diaries: 1928-1932, 1933-1937, 1938-1942, 1944-1947, 1948-1952, 1928-1952 (Box 195, Folder 6-8)
    - Diaries of ECS: 18 diaries with daily entries, 1916-1933 (Box 196, Folder 1)
    - Diaries of ECS: 17 diaries with daily entries, 1934-1950 (Box 197, Folder 1)
  - Smith, Grace Goodrich
    - Printed material: "In Memoriam" Grace Goodrich Smith 1889-1969 (Box 198, Folder 8)
  - Smith, Hart Maxcy and Margaret Jones
    Biog. info: PN (1901-1943)
    - Photographs incl. "suggestions for missionary outfit and journey", 1897, 1901, 1923 (Box 199, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1895-1900 (Box 199, Folder 2)
    - Handwritten material incl. mat. re. Student Volunteer Movement (Box 199, Folder 3)
    - Collected material: Shanghai American School Annuals, Publications, and clippings, 1925-1932 (Box 199, Folder 4-6)
    - Scrapbook of Chinese Life, 1932 (Box 199, Folder 7)
    - Two scrapbooks compiled by Ione Smith at Shanghai American School, 1929-1932 (Box OV2)
  - Smith, Howard
    Biog. info: The Rev. Howard Smith (d. 1981), a missionary under The Christian and Missionary Alliance in Central China, was kidnapped by the Chinese Communist Party under Gen. Ho Lung, and was used to teach the English to the general's troops.
    - Photocopies of newsclippings about Smith's capture; photograph of Howard Smith; photograph of the Communist Fifth Red Army soldiers after they captured the town of Hsin Hua in Hupeh; circular letter of May 1934, letters concerning the kidnapping of Howard Smith, 1934, 1971, 1983 (Box 315, Folder 18)
  - Smith, Margaret E.
    Biog. info: sister of Hart Maxcy Smith
    - Correspondence, 1937, 1938 (Box 198, Folder 1)
    - Typescript writings re. Nanking: the "fall of Nanking", "War and Missions in the Shanghai-Nanking Area", 1937 (Box 198, Folder 2)
    - Printed material re. Shanghai American School, 1930, 1934, 1938 (Box 198, Folder 3)
    - Clippings incl. series: "China in the Grip of the Reds" (North China Daily News), 1927 (Box 198, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper clippings: "Carry on for Moscow", "Missionaries in China and the Cult of 'Nationalism'", 1927, 1932 (Box 198, Folder 5)
    - Printed material: "Madame Chiang Kai-shek Makes an Announcement of Great Interest to Missionary Educationalist" (reprint from the Central China Post), Jul 1938 (Box 198, Folder 6)
    - Magazines: "China in Chaos", "The China Critic", 1927, 1932 (Box 198, Folder 7)
  - Smith, Ray
    - "The Shensi Mystery - Robbery, Revenge, or was it Conspiracy" - narrative and documents compiled by Smith, 1997 (Box 375, Folder 4)
  - Smythe, Lewis and Margaret
    United Christian Mission Society. Lewis was professor of sociology at the University of Nanking.
    - 10 circular letters, 1948-1950 (Box 378, Folder 11)
  - Spaulding, L. M.
    - Letter from Spaulding to Mary Barber, written from Ho Chow, Anhui, 1920 (Box 375, Folder 6)
  - Spreckley, J. W.
    Biog. info: CMS Mowchow, Anhsien, Chengtu, Shanghai (L.1919-L.1930)
    - Photographs: people (Box 200, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1931-1939 (Box 200, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Chinese language, tract, calling card, misc. (Box 200, Folder 3)
    - Clipping attached to note (Box 200, Folder 4)
  - Sprunger, Eva
    Sprunger was an American Methodist missionary who served in the Kutien, Fukien area from 1919 to circa 1932. She stayed in touch with her Fukien missionary colleagues after returning to her home in Berne, Indiana.
    - Circular letters written by Sprunger, 1929-1930, no date (Box 385, Folder 1)
    - Personal letters to Sprunger, from missionary colleagues, 1924-1939, no date (Box 385, Folder 2)
    - Circular letters from missionary colleagues, including Stella Bissonnette, Mary Carleton, Martha Graf, Marion Holmes, and "The Shop of Gifts for the King" in Kutien, 1930-1941 (Box 385, Folder 3-4)
      Letters provide detailed information about missionary activities and political and military events in area.
    - Translated letters from Chinese individuals, 1922-1929, no date (Box 385, Folder 5)
    - Writings of others, including regarding siege of Kutien, capture of Rev. Parsons by bandits, biography of Donald Ciu (Ciu Do Gieng), 1927-1934, no date (Box 385, Folder 6)
    - Reports of mission and church work in Kutien district, 1927, no date (Box 385, Folder 7)
    - Five photographs, including of Chinese Bible women, No date (Box 385, Folder 8)
  - Stam, Helen Priscilla
    - Photographs of Helen Priscilla Stam, killed in China by Japanese (Box 315, Folder 19)
  - Stannard, Mrs. Raymond E.
    Biog. info: ABFMS Shaohing, Che. (L.1935-L.1940)
    - Correspondence: Letter to friends of Christian hospital from Mrs. Raymond E. Stannard, 1940 (Box 200, Folder 5)
  - Stannard, Raymond E., M.D.
    Raymond Stannard was American Baptist medical missionary. He and his wife Marjorie served in Ningbo and Shaoxing, Zhejiang Province 1930-1948. Their children attended the Shanghai American School.
    - Home movies, with table of contents. The footage dates from 1933-1939 and 1946-1948 and from return trips to China by the family in 1981, 1982, 1993 (2 VHS tapes; 2 DVD copies), 1933-1948, 1981-1993 (Box 375, Folder 7)
  - Starrett, Adelia Dodge (Mrs. Oscar G.)*
    Biog. info: YMCA; MEFB Chengtu (L.1916-L.1934)
    - Photographs primarily of buildings and staff of West China Union University, Chengtu, Hospital, Chengtu, 1934 (Box 200, Folder 6)
    - Collected material: "Pioneering in West China" - articles by Spencer Lewis in The China Christian Advocate, "The Story of the Christian Colleges in China" and misc, 1933-1934 (Box 200, Folder 7-8)
  - Stewart, William R. and Anna
    YMCA, Manchuria
    - Description of trip through Mongolia, 2 circular letters from Manchuria, 1920, 1928 (Box 378, Folder 12)
  - Stirewalt, Catharine
    Biog. info: LUM Peking, Tsingtao, Shantung
    - Photograph album, well-identified - Peking, Tsingtao, Peitaiho - street scenes, funeral scenes, market, Chinese drama, Temples and other scenes, 1939-1940 (Box 260, Folder 1)
    - Typescript ms. and photograph: "Bible School Students Speak", 1939 (Box 260, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1940, 1941, 1947 (Box 260, Folder 3)
    - Printed material and notes re. China, 1936, 1940- 1949, 1979 (Box 260, Folder 4-5)
    - Typescript report: from the Lutheran Bible Institute, Tsingtao; Biographical information, 1947-1948 (Box 260, Folder 6)
    - Collected material: 2 Christian Propagation posters (oversize) (Box OVd3)
  - Stockwell, Eugene
    - Mimeo. account of trip to China, interview with Dr. and Mrs. K. H. Ting, Nanking Theol. Seminary, 1976 (Box 202, Folder 1)
  - Stone, Mary
    Mary Stone (Shi Meiyu, 1873-1954) was one of the first three Chinese women to obtain a medical degree in the U.S. Returning to China in 1896 she served a Methodist mission hospital for 25 years, with her friend Ida Kahn (Kang Cheng) and American missionary Jennie Hughes. In the 1920s Mary and Jennie resigned from the Methodist Women's Foreign Missionary Society and founded the nondenominational Shanghai Bethel Mission.
    - 20 mounted photographs depict Mary Stone, Jennie Hughes, colleagues, the Bethel Hospital in Shanghai, nursing and midwifery graduates, war orphans, a Bethel evangelistic band meeting in Hong Kong, Bethel Mission seminaries and conference., 1930s (Box 375, Folder 8)
  - Storrs, Charles and Mary (Polly)
    Biog. info: ABCFM Fukien, Shaowu 1917-1946
    - Correspondence
      - Polly to her father, 1917 Apr- 1930 Jul (Box 335, Folder 1)
      - Polly to Charles, 1931 Apr- 1939 May (Box 335, Folder 2)
      - CS and PS to siblings, 1916-1953 (Box 335, Folder 3)
      - Polly to daughter, 1932 Sep- 1934 Sep (Box 335, Folder 4)
      - CS and PS to children, 1939 -1943 (Box 335, Folder 5-7)
      - Polly's sister to father, 1923 -1924 (Box 335, Folder 8-10)
      - Polly's father to Charles, 1933 Mar-1934 Mar (Box 335, Folder 11)
      - Storr's circular letters, 1923-1943 (Box 335, Folder 12-14)
      - Storrs to/from others (alphabetically), 1946-1950, n.d. (Box 335, Folder 15-18)
      - Circular letters of others, incl. R. L. Jackson, Edward Riggs, 1946-1951 (Box 336, Folder 20-25)
      - Writings of Charles and Polly: Wecolme to Shaowu; Rethinking Missions; The Mission and the Church; A New Day for China; Poem; Margaret: My party (Box 336, Folder 26)
      - Charles' notes for sermons and talks (Box 336, Folder 27)
      - Charles' prayer journals, 1934-1942 (Box 336, Folder 28)
      - Diaries- Polly, 1918-1947 (Box 336, Folder 29-31)
      - Mission-related minutes, letter, misc, 1912-1950 (Box 337, Folder 32)
      - Info on missionaries and ministries, 1908-1949 (Box 337, Folder 33)
      - China Bulletins, 1943 May-1947 Aug (Box 337, Folder 34)
      - The Shaowu Bulletin, 1922 Sep-1926 Dec (Box 337, Folder 35)
      - Booklets on Shaowu, 1915-1939 (Box 337, Folder 36)
      - Booklets on Foochow, 1912-1937 (Box 337, Folder 37)
      - Collected material, incl. The Chinese Recorder, Chinese language material, articles, programs, songbook, 1936-1937, n.d. (Box 337, Folder 38-41)
      - Slides: Foochow and environs, including Fukien Christian University (Box 338, Folder 42-43)
      - Newsclippings (Box 338, Folder 44)
      - Travel documents, pictures, Charles' obituary; Guestbook, 1935-1964, n.d. (Box 338, Folder 45-46)
  - Stowe, Everett M.
    Biog. info: MEFB Kutien, Foochow Fukien Xn. Univ. (1923-L.1936)
    - Correspondence: Letters from Everett M. Stowe - Christmas at Fukien Christian University, 1938 (Box 202, Folder 2)
  - Strong, Anna Louise
    Anna Louise Strong (November 24, 1885 – March 29, 1970) was a twentieth-century American journalist and activist, best known for her reporting on and support for communist movements in the Soviet Union and the People's Republic of China.
    - Issues of "Letter from China" by Anna Louise Strong; articles about Strong, 1965-1970 (Box 360, Folder 3)
  - Strong, Robbins
    Biog. info: Missionary of the North China Mission of the ABCFM during the time of the Communist takeover.
    - Circular letters, 1941,1948 (Box 317, Folder 1)
    - Typescript mss.: China Visits, 1950-1978 (Box 317, Folder 2)
    - Typed and printed material: Christian documents and implications, transformation of values and attitudes in post-liberation China, 1949, 1971, 1973 (Box 317, Folder 3)
    - Typed and printed material: Christian documents and implications, 1978 (Box 317, Folder 4)
    - Typed and printed mat.: Post-Liberation, misc. articles (Box 317, Folder 5)
    - China MCC USA, 1971, 1972, 1974 (Box 317, Folder 6)
    - Typescript mat.: "Struggle for Identity" The moratorium debate in the light of the China experience, 1974 (Box 317, Folder 7)
    - Pamphlet: "China's Industry" by Roland Berger, 1981 (Box 317, Folder 8)
    - Typescript mat.: France-Asia Exchange China Dossier (In French), 1976-1978 (Box 317, Folder 9)
    - Printed ms.: China notes - NCCC/USA, 1967-1970 (Box 317, Folder 10)
    - Printed ms.: China notes - NCCC/USA, 1970-1973 (Box 317, Folder 11)
    - Printed ms.: China notes - NCCC/USA, 1973-1976 (Box 317, Folder 12)
    - Printed material: Lutheran World Federation, Marxism and China Work Information letters, 1972-1979 (Box 317, Folder 13)
    - Misc. China info: (Box 317, Folder 14)
    - Typescript material: Christian Analyses and Study of China, 1920-1979 (Box 318, Folder 1)
    - Printed material re. China general: Magazines, articles about China, 1968-1979 (Box 318, Folder 2)
    - Printed material re. China general, 1969-1971 (Box 318, Folder 3)
    - Typescript comments on China pre-liberation, 1939-1949 (Box 318, Folder 4)
    - Typed material: China study Project UK, 1976 (Box 318, Folder 5)
    - Typed and print material: Lutheran World Federation Information on China (Box 318, Folder 6)
    - Typescript ms.: "A Christian's Inquiry into the Struggle-Ethic in the Thought of Mao Tsetung" by Raymond Leslie Whitehead, 1972 (Box 318, Folder 7-8)
  - Stryker, Minnie
    Biog. info: WFMS Peking Yenching Univ.
    - Correspondence - incl. re. Sleeper Davis Hospital, 1923-1927 (Box 202, Folder 5)
  - Stuart, John Leighton
    Biog. info: PS Hangchow, Nanking, Peking Yenching Univ. (1905-1940) (see also RG 11)
    - Mimeo. copy of a letter to the Board of Trustees of Yenching Univ., Peking, re. Japanese policy, with an attached note from B. A. Garside, 1940 (Box 202, Folder 3)
  - Stuart, Warren Horton
    Biog. info: PS Hangchow, Nanking (1907-1927)
    - Typescript mat. re. "A History of Education in China", by Wang Feng-Chi and Ch'en Ch'ing-Chih. Trans. by WHS. Incl. bio. info. on the authors, table of contents, fragment of the ms. itself, introductory letter by J. Leighton Stuart, 1947 (Box 202, Folder 6)
  - Stubbs, Clifford Morgan
    Biog. info: FFMA Chengtu W. China Union Univ. (L.1916-L.1929)
    - Pamphlet: "A Life for Many, Dr Clifford M. Stubbs" by Wm. G. Sewell - with info. re. West China Union Univ. (1930) (Box 202, Folder 4)
  - Stucki, John Calvin and Marie
    Biog. info: RCUS, Peking (1924-1926), Yochow City, Hunan (1926-1927); John Calvin Stucki, medical missionary for the Reformed Church in the U.S. became superintendent of the Hoy Memorial Hospital at Yochow City, Hunan in April 1926 following a period of training in Peking. Yochow City was taken over by the Kuomintang in August, 1926. In November, the workers at the mission went on strike and students began making demands. In late 1926, educational work was discontinued at the mission and, in January of 1927, the nurses training school at Hoy was forced to close and women and children were evacuated. JCS was held captive by the Nationalists until February when he was permitted to join his wife and return to the U.S.
    - Correspondence: Articles of Agreement, letters to Merlin Hull, William mann Irvine, J.C. Vincent, 1924, 1925, 1927 (Box 245, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence to family, 1926-1927 (Box 245, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence from Marie, 1927 (Box 245, Folder 3)
    - Typescript writings, reports and news clippings, 1926, 1927 (Box 245, Folder 4)
    - Typescript ms.: Documents relating to Student and Labor unrest, 1926-1927 (Box 245, Folder 5)
    - Cassettes: 490 min. tapes re. Random reminiscences of years in China (Box 245, Folder 6)